// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Stack data structure cannot be used for",
    answer: "Allocation Resources and Scheduling",
    options: [
      "Implementation of Recursive Function",
      "Allocation Resources and Scheduling",
      "Reversing string",
      "Evaluation of string in postfix form"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Insertion and Deletion operation in Queue is known as ",
    answer: "Enqueue and Dequeue",
    options: [
      "Push and Pop",
      "Enqueue and Dequeue",
      "Insert and Delete",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "A linear list of elements in which deletion can be done from one end (front) and insertion can take place only at the other end (rear) is known as ",
    answer: "Queue",
    options: [
      "Queue",
      "Stack",
      "Tree",
      "Linked list"

    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Circular Queue is also known as ",
    answer: "Ring Buffer",
    options: [
      "Ring Buffer",
      "Square Buffer",
      "Rectangle Buffer",
      "Curve Buffer"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "A data structure in which elements can be inserted or deleted at/from both ends but not in the middle is?",
    answer: "Dequeue",
    options: [
      "Queue",
      "Circular queue",
      "Dequeue",
      "Priority queue"
    ]
  },
   {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Queues serve major role in",
    answer: "Simulation of limited resource allocation",
    options: [
      "Simulation of recursion",
      "Simulation of arbitrary linked list",
      "Simulation of limited resource allocation",
      "Simulation of heap sort"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following is not the type of queue?",
    answer: "Single ended queue",
    options: [
      "Ordinary queue",
      "Single ended queue",
      "Circular queue",
      "Priority queue"
    ]
  },{
    numb: 8,
    question: "A linear collection of data elements where the linear node is given by means of pointer is called? ",
    answer: "linked list",
    options: [
      " linked list",
      "node list",
      "primitive list",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },{
    numb: 9,
    question: ". What is the time complexity to count the number of elements in the linked list?",
    answer: "O(n)",
    options: [
      "O(1)",
      "O(n)",
      "O(logn)",
      "None of the mentioned"
    ]
  },{
    numb: 10,
    question: ". Which of these is an application of linked lists?",
    answer: "All of the mentioned",
    options: [
      "To implement file systems",
      "For separate chaining in hash-tables",
      "To implement non-binary trees",
      "All of the mentioned"
    ]
  },
  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];

fds